# 哈喽 大家好
Hello, everyone
# 上次我伯爷说漆二娃把那个虾没有做好吃
My uncle is complaining about Qi Erwa didn't make tasty shrimps last time
# 这次我伯爷自己买了一斤多 一哈好多哦四伯爷
So he bought over one jin (750g) shrimps himself this time. Uncle, how much was one jin?
# 斤多 75块钱 50一斤
I bought 75 yuan of shrimps; one jin was 50 yuan
# 我喊他让了一块钱 74块钱
I bargained with him to get a 1 yuan discount, so I spent 74 yuan
# 上次漆二娃整的不好吃
Last time Qi Erwa didn't make it good
# 这次我喊你整来看好不好吃点
So this time I want you to make it better
# 好 我们现在来开始做吧
OK, now let's start
# 四伯爷 我把这个虾枪弄来剪了
Uncle, let me fix the sharp edge of these shrimps
# 免得它戳到你的嘴巴哈
So it wouldn't hurt your mouth
# 头次漆二娃整的就是把嘴巴给我戳出血了
Last time the shrimp Qi Erwa cook made my mouth bleed
# 我还没发现是咋个整到的都不晓得
I didn't even realize how it happened
# 我们这个虾枪最好是把它剪了 非常的尖
We better cut off the sharp edge of the shrimp, it's very sharp
# 家里有小孩子或者是老人家的话一定不要这个
Especially If there's kids or elders at home
# 这个插到嘴巴有毒 会肿这个戳到嘴巴
If the sharp edge poked your lip, it would get your mouth poisoned and make them lips swollen
# 好啦 最后一个我们剪了15分钟了这里的嘎
OK, Last one. It took us 15 minutes to cut the shrimps
# 是安
Yea
# OK 好啦我们这个虾就剪好了
OK, Now we have finished preparing the shrimp.
# 我们这个剪下来的虾枪是不要的
We will not keep the sharp edge part
# 以前我拿来喂过我家的猫
I used to use them to feed my cat
# 结果猫吃了都吐了
Even my cat spitted it out
# 你还要跑
Still trying to run?
# 抓它回来
Grab it
# 跑你跑得掉呀
You can't run
# 这个不要拿给猫吃 四伯爷
Don't give this to the cat, uncle
# 倒了撒
Just throw them?
# 嗯这个必须倒了
Yes we have to throw this
# 四伯爷 这个海椒你在哪里摘得哦
Uncle, Where did you get this pepper?
# 我土里撒 第一批海椒 最先栽
I planted them, these are the first batch
# 这个辣椒我们把它切成小粒
Let's cut these peppers into small pieces
# 一样一个都够了
One from each type is enough
# 我们把这个辣椒籽去掉
Let's get rid of the seeds
# 然后我们来把这个辣椒全部切成小颗粒
Now let's cut all the peppers into small pieces
# 你把它切小颗很了夹都不好夹
If you cut it too small, it would be hard to pick up with chopsticks
# 这个是做配菜的
This
# 然后我们再切一点洋葱 就这么一片就够了
Then let's cut a bit of onion, just one slice is enough
# 这葱葱也是你栽的哦四伯爷
Uncle, did you plant these green onions too?
# 那还用说啊 农村人葱子都没得还有啥子干的
Of course, can't live without green onions
# 我们农村最多的就是葱 蒜苗 芹菜
In our village, we planted a lot of green onions, garlic sprouts and Chinese celery
# 这些东西不用去外面买
You don't need to buy these outsides
# 自己家里就可以满足了
What you planted at home can support your needs
# 是安
Yea
# 好 准备好了
OK now we are ready
# 然后这里是我上次炒的椒盐
Here is the pepper-salt powder I made from last time
# 再不用的话就回潮了 这次正好把它用了嘎
If we don't use it, it's going to be damp, let's use it this time
# 走嘛
Let’s go
# 我们先把这个虾焯一下水
Let's parboil the shrimps first
# 这个虾子还要焯哈水啊
Do we need to do that?
# 要哦
yea
# 我们这个虾焯一下水的话更好炸一些
It will be easier to fry them if you parboil the shrimps first
# 还有就是我们焯虾子的水一定要水开了再下去
Also, we have to wait for the water to boil before we put these shrimps in
# 好 下锅
OK now put them in
# 然后加点料酒
Then add some cooking wine
# 拿下去就变红了嘎
Now they have become red
# 啊 可以撒
Ah good
# 可以
great
# 好 我们焯到它腰有点变弯就把它捞起来
OK, wait till the shrimps bend to take them out
# 好 倒宽油
OK, pour Kuan You (Broad oil*)
# 放好多油哦
That's a lot of oil
# 没得好多得 最多有六七斤
That's not that much, 6 – 7 jin ( 1 jin = 500g) the most
# 啊 虾子才斤多点 油放六七斤
Ah? The shrimps are an only bit over one jin (1 jin= 500g), but you put 6-7 jin oil.
# 这会抓点粉子（淀粉）给它上点粉
Now put a handful of potato starch to mix with the shrimp
# 有这个粉子它炸出来就是脆的
The starch makes the shrimps crispy after fried
# 它才粘得上面
It will stick on to the shrimp
# 安
Great
# 粘在上面炸得泡
The starch makes shrimp's surface bubbly when frying
# 哦喔
ohh
# OK 7成油温了
OK, the oil is 70% heated.
# 这样子给它抖下去
Keep it shaky while putting the shrimps down
# 小心哦这个有点爆（油）哦
Be careful this oil is about to jump out
# 好了 我们这个虾差不多了
OK We are almost done
# 把它捞起来
Take the shrimps out
# 然后把这个油沥干净
Now drain the remainders from the oil
# 这个时候我们油就要少加一点了
Now we put less oil into the wok
# 锅中加入洋葱、青红辣椒爆香
Then add in onions and peppers to stir-fry
# 把这个弄来给它爆香
After stir-frying for a bit
# 爆香加这个（虾） 再加椒盐粉
Add the shrimps and some pepper-salt powder
# 最后加点葱葱就可以了
Then add some green onion at the end
# 放虾
Put the shrimps in
# 椒盐
Put in pepper-salt mixture
# 来 四伯爷尝哈看
Come on, try it uncle
# 试哈看嘛
Let me try
# 这个很脆
It's very crispy
# 这个我还咬得动 还是脆的
My teeth can handle this too, and it's very crispy
# 嗯 我们把虾枪去了就不怕
Yea, especially without the sharp edges of the shrimps
# 安逸
Nice
# 就不怕戳到嘴巴了噶
Won't hurt your mouth again
# 嗯
yea
# 其实做这个菜很简单
It's easy to make this dish
# 就是唯一一点不好就是要用宽油来炸
The only con is you need Kuan you ( broad oil*) to fry it
# 而且炸这个虾子的话
And after frying shrimps
# 这个油炸虾子炸不了几次这个油就会报废
You can't reuse the oil many times
# 最多3次就会报废
Three times the most
# 四伯爷 炸这个虾子
Uncle, to fry these shrimps
# 炸这个虾子很费油嘎
Needs a lot of oil
# 这个油里面要吸收这个虾子味道
The oil will absorb the taste of the shrimp
# 炸了这个油
After you fried the shrimps with the oil
# 油要变味
The oil will go bad
# 嗯 就是油要变味
Yes exactly
# 四伯爷很懂了这个 已经很懂行了
Uncle is very cultured about this
# 你慢慢都要变成行家了
You are becoming professional
# 那些东西日常生活中你都可以试出来的
You can try and learn these things from daily life experience
# 唯一的有点不好就是我炒的那个椒盐粉回潮了
The only con is the pepper-salt powder I made is a bit damped
# 没得以前那么香得了
Not as good as before
# 所以我们这个椒盐粉的话最好是现炒现用
The best time to use the pepper-salt powder is right after you made it
# 嗯
yea
# 最好就不要超过半个月
Do not leave it over for half a month
# 因为这个放太久了 四川我们这里比较潮湿
Because this has been made for a while and we have humid weather in Sichuan
# 盐都起坨坨了嘎
The salt has been damped
# 下次少炒点就是撒 用完了又炒撒
Next time just make less of it, you can always make more later
# 好了 本期视频就到这里
OK this is the end of the video
# 接着吃
Let's keep eating